Finding Aid for the Paul B. MacCready Papers, 1931-2002 MacCreadyPB
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
- Biographical and Correspondence, 5
  - Articles and other publications about MacCready, his projects and his team, 5
    - Human-powered flight, Scientific American, 1985 November; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_17 (Box 5.27, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous articles folder 2, 1985-2002; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_18 (Box 5.27, Folder 18)
    - Technological wonders, Bicycling, 1986 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_19 (Box 5.27, Folder 19)
    - The man who launched a dinosaur, Science 86, 1986 April; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_20 (Box 5.27, Folder 20)
    - Who is Bryan Allen?, Air & Space Smithsonian, Vol. 1, no. 2, 1986 June-July; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_21 (Box 5.27, Folder 21)
    - "Condor man" receives 1986 Lipper Award, Gifted Children Monthly, Vol. 7, no. 7, 1986 July-August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_22 (Box 5.27, Folder 22)
    - Paul MacCready's Quetzacoatlus Northropi, Model Aviation, 1986 August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_23 (Box 5.27, Folder 23)
    - Crash courses in flying, M Vol V, No.1, 1987 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_24 (Box 5.27, Folder 24)
    - Driven to extremes, Los Angeles Times Magazine, 1987 October 25; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_25 (Box 5.27, Folder 25)
    - Sports Car 2010, Motor Trend, 1989 January; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_26 (Box 5.27, Folder 26)
    - Education for critical thinking, Free Inquiry, Vol. 10, No. 1, 1989-1990 Winter; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_01 (Box 5.28, Folder 1)
    - Electric-powered GM car unveiled in Daily Breeze, 1990 January 4; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_02 (Box 5.28, Folder 2)
    - Flieger-Revue Exklusiv-gespräch mit Dr. Paul MacCready, Flieger-Revue '90, 1990 March; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_03 (Box 5.28, Folder 3)
    - Up, up and away, Los Angeles Times Magazine, 1990 April 22; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_04 (Box 5.28, Folder 4)
    - Paul MacCready and his marvelous machines, Reader's Digest, 1991 August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_05 (Box 5.28, Folder 5)
    - Lessons from an aeronautics master, Design News, 1991 August 26; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_06 (Box 5.28, Folder 6)
    - Unexpected challenges to a sustainable world (report on panel discussion moderated by Paul MacCready), Engineering & Science, 1992 Spring; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_07 (Box 5.28, Folder 7)
    - Paul MacCready: inventor, Creativity: Conversations With 28 Who Excel (Momentum Books Ltd), 1993; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_08 (Box 5.28, Folder 8)
    - Interview with Paul MacCready, Think, 1993 December; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_09 (Box 5.28, Folder 9)
    - The first human-powered flight, 1995; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_10 (Box 5.28, Folder 10)
    - In history: Orlick II, Sailplane & electric Modeler, Vol. 3 No. 2, 1997 Winter; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_11 (Box 5.28, Folder 11)
    - The boy who built a plane to fly for ever, The Times, 1998 July 8; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_12 (Box 5.28, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous articles about Helios, Pathfinder and Centurion, folder 1, 1998-1999; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_13 (Box 5.28, Folder 13)
    - Paul MacCready, Esquire, 1999 November; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_14 (Box 5.28, Folder 14)
    - Pursuing soaring visions, Soaring, 2000 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_15 (Box 5.28, Folder 15)
    - A man to know, The Adventurers' Club News, 2000 November; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_16 (Box 5.28, Folder 16)
    - Inventors dream makers: Paul MacCready, Time, 2000 December 4; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_17 (Box 5.28, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous articles about Helios, Pathfinder and Centurion, folder 2, 2001-2002; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_18 (Box 5.28, Folder 18)
    - Paul MacCready, Discover, 2002 July; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_19 (Box 5.28, Folder 19)
    - Fruits of invention/Beyond Icarus/Q & A, World Technology Intelligence, 2002 July-August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_20 (Box 5.28, Folder 20)
    - Microbats, broken skulls, rocket girls & prehistoric beach bears, LA Weekly, Vol. 24 No. 50, 2002 November 1-7; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_21 (Box 5.28, Folder 21)
    - To dream the improbable dream, and make it soar, Los Angeles Times, 2002 December 23; MacCreadyPB_05_05_028_22 (Box 5.28, Folder 22)
- Miscellaenous Material, 6
  - Meteorology Research, Inc., 1
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1950 -1970; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_01 (Box 6.1, Folder 1)
    - Free balloon flight (Mt. Withington, New Mexico), 1953 August 23; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_02 (Box 6.1, Folder 2)
    - Munitalp atmosperic research project, 1953-1954; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_03 (Box 6.1, Folder 3)
    - MRI correspondence, 1956-1958; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_04 (Box 6.1, Folder 4)
    - Project Skyfire, 1957; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_05 (Box 6.1, Folder 5)
    - Electric storm in Pasadena/Altadena area, 1957; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_06 (Box 6.1, Folder 6)
    - LARP meteorological sounding system and other papers, 1958-1963; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_07 (Box 6.1, Folder 7)
    - LARP and HARP papers including homing radio. Folder 1, 1958; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_08 (Box 6.1, Folder 8)
    - Temperature pressure recording, 1959; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_09 (Box 6.1, Folder 9)
    - LARP and HARP papers including homing radio. Folder 2, 1959-1960; MacCreadyPB_06_01_001_10 (Box 6.1, Folder 10)
    - LARP and HARP papers including homing radio. Folder 3, 1959-1960; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_01 (Box 6.2, Folder 1)
    - LARP and HARP papers and small apparatus samples, 1960-1967; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_02 (Box 6.2, Folder 2)
    - Instruments brochures, 1961; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_03 (Box 6.2, Folder 3)
    - Radio control papers, 1962-1967; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_04 (Box 6.2, Folder 4)
    - The Summit corporation, 1963; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_05 (Box 6.2, Folder 5)
    - Meteorology Research annual report, 1964; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_06 (Box 6.2, Folder 6)
    - MRI technical reports, folder 1, 1964-1969; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_07 (Box 6.2, Folder 7)
    - Gyro parts drawings, 1967; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_08 (Box 6.2, Folder 8)
    - Homing microdrone, 1967-1969; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_09 (Box 6.2, Folder 9)
    - Logic electronics, 1969; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_10 (Box 6.2, Folder 10)
    - Shoreline diffusion program. Oceanside, California. Vol. 1, 1969; MacCreadyPB_06_01_002_11 (Box 6.2, Folder 11)
    - MRI technical reports, folder 2, 1969 November; MacCreadyPB_06_01_003_01 (Box 6.3, Folder 1)
    - MRI technical reports, folder 3, 1971-1972; MacCreadyPB_06_01_003_02 (Box 6.3, Folder 2)
  - Soaring and gliding, 2
    - How can I become a soaring pilot?, undated; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_03 (Box 6.3, Folder 3)
    - Glider sketch from New York State Aviation School, 1937 May 11; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_04 (Box 6.3, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1938-1949; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_05 (Box 6.3, Folder 5)
    - Glider data, 1942-1943; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_06 (Box 6.3, Folder 6)
    - Lopez sailplane, 1946; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_07 (Box 6.3, Folder 7)
    - Schweizer Model SGS 1-21, 1946 August 14; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_08 (Box 6.3, Folder 8)
    - World championship in soaring (Orebro, Sweden), 1950; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_09 (Box 6.3, Folder 9)
    - World soaring championship (Madrid, Spain), 1952; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_10 (Box 6.3, Folder 10)
    - World glider championship (France), 1956; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_11 (Box 6.3, Folder 11)
    - Championnats du Monde de Vol a Voile (Saone-et-Loire), 1956; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_12 (Box 6.3, Folder 12)
    - World gliding championship (Leizno, Poland), 1958; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_13 (Box 6.3, Folder 13)
    - Technical symposium on soaring (Soaring Society of America, Los Angeles), 1961; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_14 (Box 6.3, Folder 14)
    - The 1999 National Convention of the Soaring Society of America, MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_15 (Box 6.3, Folder 15)
    - Breathing apparatus for glider, c. 1950 - 1965; MacCreadyPB_06_02_003_16 (Box 6.3, Folder 16)
  - Educational Programs and other papers, 3
    - Thinking skill materials, 1982-1989; MacCreadyPB_06_03_004_01 (Box 6.4, Folder 1)
    - Educational programs: correspondence and papers, 1991-1999; MacCreadyPB_06_03_004_02 (Box 6.4, Folder 2)
    - Institute for Educational Advancement, Apprenticeship Program; Folder 1, 1999-2000; MacCreadyPB_06_03_004_03 (Box 6.4, Folder 3)
    - Institute for Educational Advancement, Apprenticeship Program; Folder 2, 1999-2000; MacCreadyPB_06_03_004_04 (Box 6.4, Folder 4)
    - Institute for Educational Advancement, Apprenticeship Program; Folder 3, 2000; MacCreadyPB_06_03_004_05 (Box 6.4, Folder 5)
    - Institute for Educational Advancement, Apprenticeship Program; Folder 4, 2000; MacCreadyPB_06_03_004_06 (Box 6.4, Folder 6)
  - Other projects and miscellaneous papers, 4
    - Articles by Paul MacCready, Sr., undated; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_01 (Box 6.5, Folder 1)
    - Propellers for model airplanes and other papers and drawings, ca 1940; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_02 (Box 6.5, Folder 2)
    - Free flying gas model airplanes; written with the help of MacCready's father, 1940-1942; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_03 (Box 6.5, Folder 3)
    - Designing a gas model airplane; Gas model design; written with the help of MacCready's father, 1942; 1943; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_04 (Box 6.5, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous objects, 1954; undated; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_05 (Box 6.5, Folder 5)
    - Cotton farm, folder 1, 1955-1956; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_06 (Box 6.5, Folder 6)
    - Stereo cloud photography equipment, 1956; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_07 (Box 6.5, Folder 7)
    - Balloon flight, 1957; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_08 (Box 6.5, Folder 8)
    - Cotton farm, folder 2, 1957-1958; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_09 (Box 6.5, Folder 9)
    - Flattop boat project, 1970-1971; MacCreadyPB_06_04_005_10 (Box 6.5, Folder 10)
    - Gen-Mar, Inc., 1970-1976; MacCreadyPB_06_04_006_01 (Box 6.6, Folder 1)
    - Woolacombe Bird, 1974-1975; MacCreadyPB_06_04_006_02 (Box 6.6, Folder 2)
    - Original design sketch of Solar Seagull, 1980 April 12; MacCreadyPB_06_04_006_03; framed sketch on napkin (Box 6.6, Folder 3)
    - Lindbergh Awards - Nominating committee and board involvement, 1981; 1989; 1992; MacCreadyPB_06_04_006_04 (Box 6.6, Folder 4)
    - Community learning and information network (CLIN), 1994; MacCreadyPB_06_04_006_05 (Box 6.6, Folder 5)
    - Illusion Works, 1996-1997; MacCreadyPB_06_04_006_06 (Box 6.6, Folder 6)
    - Chrysler Design Award Champions trophy, 2002; MacCreadyPB_06_04_006_07; correspondence and sketches (Box 6.6, Folder 7)
    - Scientific American covers, Glider tag and menu, 1915-1918; 1945; 1956; MacCreadyPB_06_04_007_01 (Box 6.7, Folder 1)
    - Barograph reports, Ribbon, and new clipping, 1946-1948; MacCreadyPB_06_04_007_02 (Box 6.7, Folder 2)
    - Photographs, unsorted, Undated; MacCreadyPB_06_04_007_03 (Box 6.7, Folder 3)
    - Photo album, Undated; MacCreadyPB_06_04_007_04 (Box 6.7, Object 1)
    - Letter,illustration,photographic negative, article, 1989-1990; undated; MacCreadyPB_06_04_008_01 (6.8, Folder 1)
    - Award certificates, 1978; 1991; MacCreadyPB_06_04_008_02 (6.8, Folder 2)
- Audio-Visual Material, 7
  - Photographic Slides, 1
    - Aircraft, Solar and Human Powered Vehicles and AeroVironment
    - Model airplanes and gliders: includes photographs of MacCready with award winning planes and images of newspapers and magazine articles. 2 Sheets., ca. 1937-1941; 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_01_001_01; Black and White 35mm slides (Box 7.1, Folder 1)
    - Aircraft, 1946-1980; MacCreadyPB_07_01_001_02; Black and White and Color 35mm slides (Box 7.1, Folder 2)
    - Soaring (gliding) competitions, 1954-1956; MacCreadyPB_07_01_001_03; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.1, Folder 3)
    - Cloud seeding and meteorology, 1956-1974; MacCreadyPB_07_01_001_04; 35 mm slides (Box 7.1, Folder 4)
      See LARP/HARP papers including Homing Radio folders 1 & 2
    - Meteorology Research, Inc. - HARP, LARP, 7 sheets, 1958 - 1964; 1967; MacCreadyPB_07_01_001_05; 35 mm slides (Box 7.1, Folder 5)
    - Hang Gliding, 1973-1979; MacCreadyPB_07_01_001_06; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.1, Folder 6)
    - Human Powered Vehicles (HPV), 1974-1995; MacCreadyPB_07_01_001_07; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.1, Folder 7)
    - Gossamer Aircraft, 1976-1979; 1989-1993; MacCreadyPB_07_01_001_08; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.1, Folder 8)
    - Solar Challenger: 2 sheets including aerial shots, personnel, pilots and production, 1981-1982; MacCreadyPB_07_01_002_01; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.2, Folder 1)
    - Bionic Bat: 2 sheets including development, cyclists/pilots training, crew and flights, 1983-1984; MacCreadyPB_07_01_002_02; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.2, Folder 2)
    - Quetzalcoatlus Northropi (QN or Pterodactyl), 1985-1988; MacCreadyPB_07_01_002_03; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.2, Folder 3)
    - Solar Challenge (Sunrayce), Australia, 1987-1988; MacCreadyPB_07_01_002_04; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.2, Folder 4)
    - Solar Challenges (Sunrayces), 1990; 1993; MacCreadyPB_07_01_002_05; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.2, Folder 5)
    - Aerovironment, 1988-1996; MacCreadyPB_07_01_002_06; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.2, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Aircraft, 1965-1997; MacCreadyPB_07_01_002_07; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.2, Folder 7)
    - Family, relatives, friends, vacation and leisure
    - Slides, 1930-1947; MacCreadyPB_07_01_002_08; Black and White 35mm slides (Box 7.2, Folder 8)
    - Slides, 1954-1956; MacCreadyPB_07_01_002_09; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.2, Folder 9)
    - Slides, 1956-1957; MacCreadyPB_07_01_003_01; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.3, Folder 1)
    - Slides, 1957-1960; MacCreadyPB_07_01_003_02; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.3, Folder 2)
    - Slides, 1960-1964; MacCreadyPB_07_01_003_03; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.3, Folder 3)
    - Slides, 1964-1965; MacCreadyPB_07_01_003_04; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.3, Folder 4)
    - Slides, 1965-1967; MacCreadyPB_07_01_003_05; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.3, Folder 5)
    - Slides, 1967-1969; MacCreadyPB_07_01_003_06; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.3, Folder 6)
    - Slides, 1968-1970; MacCreadyPB_07_01_004_01; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.4, Folder 1)
    - Slides, 1970; MacCreadyPB_07_01_004_02; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.4, Folder 2)
    - Slides, 1970-1972; MacCreadyPB_07_01_004_03; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.4, Folder 3)
    - Slides, 1972-1974; MacCreadyPB_07_01_004_04; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.4, Folder 4)
    - Slides, 1974-1978; MacCreadyPB_07_01_004_05; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.4, Folder 5)
    - Slides, 1978-1980; MacCreadyPB_07_01_004_06; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.4, Folder 6)
    - Slides, 1981-1983; MacCreadyPB_07_01_005_01; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.5, Folder 1)
    - Slides, 1984-1985; MacCreadyPB_07_01_005_02; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.5, Folder 2)
    - Slides, 1985-1986; MacCreadyPB_07_01_005_03; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.5, Folder 3)
    - Slides, 1987-1989; MacCreadyPB_07_01_005_04; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.5, Folder 4)
    - Slides, 1989-1990; MacCreadyPB_07_01_005_05; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.5, Folder 5)
    - Slides: 8 sheets including friends, family, skiing, flying and Conneticut, 1991; MacCreadyPB_07_01_005_06; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.5, Folder 6)
    - Slides, 1992-1993; MacCreadyPB_07_01_005_07; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.5, Folder 7)
    - Slides, 1993-1995; MacCreadyPB_07_01_006_01; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.6, Folder 1)
    - Slides, 1995-1997; MacCreadyPB_07_01_006_02; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.6, Folder 2)
    - Slides: Yangtze trip, 10 sheets, 1996; MacCreadyPB_07_01_006_03; Color 35mm slides (Box 7.6, Folder 3)
  - Photographic prints and negatives, 2
    - Aircraft - Soaring/Gliders
      From Soaring Society of America.
    - Airhoppers Gliding & Soaring Club, Hicksville, Long Island, ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_01 (Box 7.7, Folder 1)
    - Army glider, ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_02 (Box 7.7, Folder 2)
    - Parker Leonard, et al., ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_03 (Box 7.7, Folder 3)
    - Loomis & Hall photographs, ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_04 (Box 7.7, Folder 4)
    - Minimoa, ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_05 (Box 7.7, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous gliders (Folder 1), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_06 (Box 7.7, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous gliders (Folder 2), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_07 (Box 7.7, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous gliders (Folder 3), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_08 (Box 7.7, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous gliders (Folder 4), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_09 (Box 7.7, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous gliders (Folder 5), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_10 (Box 7.7, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous gliders (Folder 6), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_11 (Box 7.7, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous gliders (Folder 7), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_12 (Box 7.7, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous locations, ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_13 (Box 7.7, Folder 13)
    - Monitor Wolf Pictures: Best of Wolf, ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_14 (Box 7.7, Folder 14)
    - People (Folder 1), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_15 (Box 7.7, Folder 15)
    - People (Folder 2), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_16 (Box 7.7, Folder 16)
    - Sailfly and Simplifly (drawings), ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_17 (Box 7.7, Folder 17)
    - Nomad, 1939 August; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_18 (Box 7.7, Folder 18)
    - Wurtsboro Airport Meet, 1939 October 14-15; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_19 (Box 7.7, Folder 19)
    - TG -3, Elmira. Marston & [Parker] Leonard, ca. 1942; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_20 (Box 7.7, Folder 20)
    - Skid test, USAF Maxton Army Air Base, 1944 March 16; MacCreadyPB_07_02_007_21 (Box 7.7, Folder 21)
    - Early years
    - Early childhood photos, ca. 1934 - 1943; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_01; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 1)
    - Judy and Kirke Leonard, ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_02; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 2)
    - Tippy Leonard, ca. 1935 - 1945; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_03; Black and White negatives (Box 7.8, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1935 - 1985; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_04; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 4)
    - Bishop scenes and vapor trails, ca. 1940 - 1950; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_05; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 5)
    - High school and college, ca. 1945 - 1952; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_06; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 6)
    - Gliding - Orlik, Bréguet 901, ca. 1946 - 1956; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_07; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 7)
    - Paul MacCready Sr. and Jr., ca. 1950 - 1960; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_08; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 8)
    - Passport photos, 1954 April 23; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_09; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 9)
    - Free Balloon Flight Paul MacCready and Charles Moore, 1957 July-August; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_10; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 10)
    - Meteorology Research, Inc. - HARP, 1960 - 1961; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_11; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 11)
    - Meteorology Research, Inc. - LARP, 1961; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_12; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 12)
    - Caltech Alumni Seminar Day, 1978; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_13; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 13)
    - Worcester Polytechnic Institute Commencement, 1980 May 31; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_14; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 14)
    - Honorary Doctorates from Stevens Institute of Technology and Yale, 1980 May 22; 1983 May 23; MacCreadyPB_07_02_008_15; Black and White photographs (Box 7.8, Folder 15)
      Photos by T. Charles Erickson, Yale University, Office of Public Information
    - Flight and vehicle projects: Gossamer Albatross, Gossamer Condor, Quetzacoatlus, Sunraycer
    - Gossamer Condor, 1973; 1977; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_01; Black and White photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 1)
    - Tyler MacCready - Walkalong Glider, ca. 1975-1985; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_02; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 2)
    - Gossamer Condor - National Air & Space Museum Event, ca. 1977 - 1980; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_03; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 3)
    - Gossamer Albatross - Miscellaneous (Folder 1), 1977 - 1981; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_04; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 4)
    - Gossamer Albatross - Harper Dry Lake Bed Trials, 1978 - 1979; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_05; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 5)
    - Gossamer Albatross - Miscellaneous (Folder 2), 1978 - 1980; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_06; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 6)
    - Gossamer Albatross - Bryan Allen, 1979; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_07; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 7)
    - Gossamer Albatross - Miscellaneous (Folder 3), ca. 1979; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_08; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 8)
    - Gossamer Albatross - England and France, 1979 January - February; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_09; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 9)
    - Gossamer Albatross - Miscellaneous (Folder 4), 1979 January - February; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_10; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 10)
    - Building the Gossamer Albatross at Terminal Island, CA, 1979 March; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_11; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 11)
    - Members of Gossamer Albatross team, et al., 1979 May - June; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_12; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 12)
    - Gossamer Albatross - Crossing the English Channel, 1979 June 12; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_13; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 13)
    - Gossamer Albatross Kremer Prize Award Ceremony, 1979 December; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_14; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 14)
    - Gossamer Penguin, 1979-1980; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_15; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 15)
    - Solar Challenger - Press photos, 1981; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_16; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 16)
    - Quetzacoatlus Northropi, 1985; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_17; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 17)
    - Sunraycer (Folder 1), 1987; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_18; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 18)
    - Sunraycer (Folder 2), 1987; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_19; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 19)
    - Sunraycer (Folder 3), 1987; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_20; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 20)
    - AeroVironment - Miscellaneous, ca. 1987-2001; undated; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_21; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 21)
    - GM Sunraycer and other cars - Press photos, 1987-1988; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_22; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 22)
    - Sunraycer - Press photos, 1987 September; MacCreadyPB_07_02_009_23; Color photographs (Box 7.9, Folder 23)
    - Later years
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1985 - 2001; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_01; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 1)
    - Lecture photos, 1988; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_02; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 2)
    - National Air and Space Museum Award, 1988 October 21; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_03; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 3)
    - Portraits of Paul MacCready, ca. 1995 - 2004; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_04 (Box 7.10, Folder 4)
    - Art Center Anthropropulsion Exhibit/Vacation Photos, 1996 August; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_05; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 5)
    - Trike experiments/Model airplanes/Gliders, 1997; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_06; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 6)
    - Gossamer Condor at National Air and Space Museum, 1997 April; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_07; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 7)
    - Yale 1947 50th class reunion, 1997 May 29-30; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_08; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 8)
    - Black Sheep Squadron model airplanes/Nevada Inventors Hall of Fame/Christmas at Olympic, 1997 December - 1998 January; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_09; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 9)
    - Ralph Coats Roe Award, 1998; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_10; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 10)
    - Micromodels and wind turbines, 1998 March; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_11; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 11)
    - Erwin Hauer in his studio/Miscellaneous, 1998 October November; MacCreadyPB_07_02_010_12; Color photographs (Box 7.10, Folder 12)